onnanoko hajimemashita
A tired girl starts her day
tameiki wa bioron no shirabe ni nite
With a sigh like the moan of a violin
akai mi hajikechatta
A cherry bursts in her mouth
mada anata wo shiranai
This was before we had met
konna koto hajimetette
This is the first time I've ever felt like this
manazashi wa aku no hana sakimidarete mo
I could see that your pretty eyes were filled with contempt
ie e to tsuzuku
But I had to go home
basu sutoppu demo anata wa tsurenai
Even at the bus stop, you gave me the cold shoulder
karameta hanabi myaku utsu
The fireworks in the sky pulse
koi no shiruetto
In a silhouette of love
karui mahou
With a little magic,
usotsuki na kuchibiru
Two sets of lying lips
sou kasaneteru
Lock together
ano ne
You see
nee kamisama
God...
warui ko ni naritai yo
I'd like to be a naughty girl
ii ko ni shiteru kara
I'm tired of being good
onegai dayo
So, please
zurui koto sasetoite
It's for a good reason
ii koto shitai nara
So let me be bad for once
sukaato hirogaesu shite
By flipping my skirt
sugu kaeru yo
I'll be back soon
doyoubi wa haresou da
It looks like Saturday is going to be sunny
kamisama hajimemashita
God, it has already started
The joys of summer break are just around the corner.
（講釈師）
もうすぐ楽しい夏休み
There's our darling heroine Nanami simply beaming with joy.
我らが主人公 奈々生(ななみ)ちゃんも
どこか浮かれ模様
お友達の
あみちゃん ケイちゃんと―
She's with her friends Ami and Kei, and they're excitedly making fun vacation plans!
うきうき夏のレジャー計画真っ盛り
（ケイ）
おい ナレーター
絵と全然違うだろうが
Hey, Narrator, that's not what's in the frame at all!
Oh, you're right.
（講釈師）
あ… ホントだ
Get your head in the game!
（ケイ）
暑さぼけしてんじゃねえぞ
（講釈師）
すいませーん
My bad.
そうでした そうでした
Ah, yes, I remember now.
ああ　前回 花開いた恋心は
その翌日に見事 玉砕
Last time, she discovered love was blooming in her heart and soon after had it ripped out and stomped on.
How could she not be bummed out after that?
これが
どよんとせずに おらりょうか
（あみ）
ねえねえ
夏休み みんなで海に行かない？
Hey, how about we all go to the beach during the break?
What do you think?
ねえ 桃園(ももぞの)さん
Beach... Sounds good... Love to go... Yodele-hee-hoo or something...
（奈々生）
海いいね　行きたいね
やっほーなんてね
桃園さん それ山　しっかりして
That's the mountains! Pull yourself together, girl!
The guy she opened her heart and soul to basically told her to take a cold shower. I kinda get it.
（ケイ）
告白した相手に
頭冷やせって言われちゃあね
無理ないわ
Guess you're still not hungry?
今日も食欲ないの？
お弁当 全然食べてないじゃん
You haven't touched your lunch at all.
Yeah.
食べないと駄目だよ 倒れちゃうよ
You have to eat something, or you'll pass out.
Indeed.
（巴衛(ともえ)）
全くだな
朝も ろくに食べていないのに―
You scarcely had anything to eat in the morning,
and now you're refusing lunch? What is the meaning of this?
昼食まで手付かずとは
どういうつもりだ
Is this your idea of fasting or something?
断食でもしているつもりか
（奈々生）
心の整理をつけたくても―
I want to stay in control of my feelings,
but it's hard when he can show up out of nowhere and catch me off guard.
いつでもどこでも
巴衛が目に飛び込んでくる
I-I'm just not hungry.
（奈々生）しょ… 食欲が出なくて
（巴衛）出せ
Too bad.
Please stop.
やめてよ 巴衛君
She hasn't recovered from being rejected by you yet!
桃園さんは 巴衛君に
フラれたショックから―
Rejected
まだ立ち直ってないんだから
I can't get a grip on my emotions.
（奈々生）
心が落ち着かないよ
Out of the way, Strawberry.
（巴衛）どけ いちご
（あみ）うわーっ！
If you refuse to eat, then you leave me no choice but to pry your mouth open and force feed you.
飯が食えんと言うのなら―
俺が口をこじあけてでも
食わせてやる
What?!
うわーっ！　しいたけ！
Shiitake mushroom!
落ち着かないのは 私だけで―
I'm the only one whose feelings changed.
巴衛は いつもと変わらない
Tomoe's the same as always.
There's only one exception.
ただ一つ変わったのは―
私に触れなくなったことだけ
He's doing everything he can to avoid touching me.
桃園さん 元気出して
私が付いてるからね
Cheer up, Momozono!
I'm here for you!
一緒に海に行って遊ぼう
I'm dying to take you to the beach.
体 動かせば
きっと気分も軽くなるよ
We'll have so much fun that you'll forget all about what happened.
Yeah, maybe I will go.
うん 行こっかな
How about Saturday?
じゃあ 土曜日ね
That's fine, but do you guys even have swimsuits?
いいけど
あんたたち水着持ってんの？
What? Uh...
えっ えっと…
The beach?
（巴衛）
海？
The God Goes To The Beach
（瑞希(みずき)）
フフフ… こんにちは
Hello! ls Nanami here—
（瑞希）奈々生ちゃんいる？
（鬼切(おにきり)）わあっ
What do you mean I can't go?!
行っちゃ駄目ってどういうことよ！
You just cannot go to the beach!
（巴衛）
とにかく海は駄目だ
Why not?! Nekota went out of her way to invite me along!
何でよ　猫田(ねこた)さんが
せっかく誘ってくれたのに
横暴よ
This is unfair!
（虎徹(こてつ)）
落ち着かれませ 奈々生様
Please calm down, Lady Nanami.
The ocean is a hotbed of demonic creatures.
海は魔物の巣窟だ
If you were human,
人なら いざ知らず―
土地神のお前を１人で行かせて
何かあったらどうする
you could go, but you are a land god, and I cannot risk something happening to you.
Also, I cannot go into the ocean to protect you,
それに 俺は海には入れない
だから駄目だ
so the answer is no.
I won't be alone! I'll be with my friends!
１人じゃない 友達と一緒だもん
（巴衛）
友達？　そいつらが何の役に立つ
Friends?
Can your friends stand up to demons?
Then want me to come with you to the beach?
（瑞希）
じゃあ
僕が付いてってあげようか？　海
Mizuki...
瑞希
It's the ocean!
海だ！
海！
The ocean!
Yeah, "It's the ocean!" Whatever.
“海だ！”は ともかく―
何で こいつら付いてきてんのよ
But why are these guys here?!
Hello!
こんにちは
If we have guys in the damn group, no one will come cruising for us!
男連れだと
ナンパが寄ってこねえだろうが
空気読んでこいよ
Get a clue about the scene before you come!
Cruising?
Cruising
難破？
I'm not talking about a damn ship!
Kei told me that she broke up with her boyfriend yesterday.
（あみ）
ケイちゃん
昨日 彼氏と別れちゃったんだって
You'll be in the way if you hang around us!
（奈々生）
結局 巴衛まで来ちゃったし
胃がきりきりするな
In the end, Tomoe wound up coming with us too.
My stomach hurts.
準備できたよ
All ready!
You look like a toddler with that thing.
あんた小学生みたい
Well, I can't swim without it.
だって あみ泳げないんだもん
桃園さんはどう？　その水着
What about you, Momozono? How's the swimsuit?
Yeah...
It's really cute.
すごくかわいい
貸してくれてありがとう
ケイちゃん
Thank you for loaning it to me.
こんなの初めて着たよ
I've never worn anything like this!
No problem.
いいって いいって
隣で Ｔシャツで
泳がれたくないからね
I don't want you swimming next to me in a t-shirt.
Why don't you go show off to your two friends?
見せてきてあげたら？
連れの２人にさ
（ケイ）にしても あの２人
（奈々生）うん？
But those two...
Off
On
Their
Own
Off
On
Their
Own
They don't look like they're
interested in swimming at all.
（ケイ）
全く
泳ぐ気ないって感じだね
The Distribution
of Spirit Power
L-Let's hurry up and get in the ocean.
（奈々生）
は… 早く海入ろう
You sure?
いいの？
Positive! It's their fault for following me!
いいの
勝手に付いてきただけだから
Somehow, I'm suddenly feeling all self-conscious.
（奈々生）
何か急に恥ずかしくなってきた
（あみ）
桃園さん こっちこっち
Momozono! Over here! Over here!
Do I seem okay?
（奈々生）
大丈夫かな 私　変じゃない？
Not awkward?
Does the swimsuit... look good on me?
水着 似合ってる？
What are you doing here, Tomoe?
何で来たのさ 巴衛君
I could ask you the same thing. Die.
こっちのせりふだ 死ね
Girls these days are so shameless, aren't they?
今どきの子って破廉恥だね
They're wandering around in practically nothing out there.
あんな
裸同然の格好でうろうろしてさ
It's enough to turn even human guys into beastly spirits.
あれじゃ
人間の男だって妖怪化しちゃうよね
巴衛君
来てよかったって思ってるでしょう
Are you at least having somewhat of a good time here?
I must admit I'm surprised you came here at all.
でも まさか
本当に来るとは思わなかったな
And in case you forgot, I do know why you can't go into the ocean.
僕 巴衛君が
どうして海に入れないか知ってるよ
巴衛君のこと大嫌いだけど―
I hate your guts,
but I'll be nice and keep it a secret from Nanami.
奈々生ちゃんには
言わないでいてあげるよ
Nanami! Mind if I join you over there?!
奈々生ちゃん
僕も そっち行っていい？
Sure!
（奈々生）
ねえ 見て
きれいな貝 見つけたの
Hey, look! I found a pretty shell!
ほら
See?
Yes...
行こう 奈々生ちゃん
巴衛君は 海が嫌いなんだってさ
Let's go, Nanami.
Tomoe says he hates the ocean.
Okay.
Let's go find all kinds of shells.
（瑞希）
いろんな貝
見つけようね ね～
Casually touching what is off-limits to me...
（巴衛）
俺が触れないものに
気安く触りやがって
あのくそ蛇野郎
Damn that bastard snake.
So our little white serpent boy swims.
（乙比古(おとひこ)）
白蛇の坊や 泳ぐのね
I think I might go, too.
私も行こうかしら
ウフッ
Peek.
ちらっ
See you later.
（ミカゲ）
いってらっしゃい
ミカゲ君も行きましょうよ
You should come with me, Mikage.
（ミカゲ）
これ以上 近づくと―
If I get any closer, Tomoe will definitely recognize me.
巴衛に
気付かれるかもしれないからね
Okay, but mind explaining why you're dressed like an Eskimo at the beach?
ていうか ビーチに
その暑苦しいコートって何
It's part of my image.
これが僕のイメージですから
Ah, yes. Well, I can certainly respect that.
まあ でも確かにそうね
After you abandoned him for twenty whole years, you're now hiding so close by, secretly watching over him.
20年間も放っておいて―
こんな近くで
物陰からこっそり見守っていた―
I imagine he'd kill you if he found you.
なんてこと 彼が知ったら
さすがに殺されるわよ
Tomoe wouldn't do that.
（ミカゲ）
巴衛は そんなことしないよ
せいぜい跳び蹴りくらいだよ
At worst, he'd jump-kick me.
（乙比古）
ウフフッ
He may not look it, but Tomoe does have a compassionate side to him.
巴衛君 ああ見えて
情け深いところがあるものね
But I wonder how he will be toward that human girl.
でも あの人間の娘にはどうかしら
さてと
ちょっと泳いでくるわね
Now then, I'm going to go for a quick swim.
アハハッ
我が友人ながら
とても神には見えない
He's my friend, but it's easy to forget he's a god sometimes.
Still...
とはいえ―
夏ですね
It is summer.
I'm here anyway, so I suppose I'll go for a swim.
せっかくだから一泳ぎしますか
わあ きれい
Wow! It's pretty!
You can have it.
（奈々生）
あげるよ
You sure?
いいの？　ありがとう
Thanks.
Are you having fun?
海 楽しい？
Yeah, the water feels amazing.
うん すごく気持ちいい
That's good.
そっか
Nanami, I'm glad you're feeling better.
奈々生ちゃん
元気になってよかったね
（あみ）
ウフフ… うわ～！　フフフ…
（乙比古）
ウフフ…
Pardon my little meddling.
ちょっと ごめんなさいね
Nekota?
（奈々生）
猫田さん？
I knew it already, but seawater still feels icky.
やっぱ海水は気持ち悪いや
いち抜けた
I'm out.
Oh? What's wrong, Tomoe?
あれ 巴衛君どうしたの？
元から怖い顔が 更に怖い顔だけど
Your face is more furry and frightening than usual!
巴衛　あみと桃園さんが
Tomoe! It's Ami and Momozono!
Are you all right, Nanami?
（巴衛）
大丈夫か 奈々生
（奈々生）
巴衛　猫田さんが…
Tomoe! It's Nekota!
猫田さんがいなくなっちゃったの
Nekota's disappeared!
潜って捜したんだけど見つからない
猫田さん泳げないのに
I dove down looking for her, but I couldn't find her!
And she can't swim!
お願い 巴衛　猫田さんを
Please, Tomoe! Find her...
Leave it to me.
（巴衛）
任せろ
（瑞希）
あれ いいの？　巴衛君
Really? Are you sure about this, Tomoe?
Nanami has requested my help in her time of need.
ほかならぬ奈々生の頼みとあらば
しかたあるまい
What choice do I have?
Ami...
（巴衛）
あみ　あみ
Ami!
Time to go back.
帰るぞ
Nekota!
（奈々生）
猫田さん！
Ami!
（ケイ）あみ
（奈々生）猫田さん 大丈夫？
Are you all right?!
I'm okay. I just swallowed a lot of water.
大丈夫
お水いっぱい飲んじゃった
Stupid Ami! Honestly! You had us so worried!
ばかあみ
（ケイ）もう本当に心配かけて
（奈々生）よかった
Thank goodness.
I'm sorry.
（あみ）ごめん
（ケイ）よかった…
I'm so glad!
Tomoe.
（奈々生）
巴衛
ありがとう
Thank you.
Very good.
Yes, thank you, Tomoe.
（龍王(りゅうおう)）
ありがとう 巴衛
So nice of you to drop by the ocean for a visit.
海に入ってきてくれてありがとう
Thanks to that, I've finally been able to find you.
おかげで やっと
お前を見つけることができたよ
right up
Next part coming
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
（龍王）
お前が水遊びしてくれるのを
ずっと待ってたぜ 巴衛
I've been waiting all this time for you to come play in the water, Tomoe.
誰？
Who are you?!
I am the great Dragon King, ruler of the seas.
（龍王）
海を統べる この龍王様の顔
見忘れたわけじゃあるまいな
You better not have forgotten!
Tomoe?
（奈々生）
巴衛？
Kei! Nekota!
（奈々生）
ケイちゃん 猫田さん
Sorry, but I'm gonna ask the
spectators to stay out of this.
（龍王）
悪いがギャラリーには
遠慮してもらうぜ
It's time for me to collect a debt from an old friend.
これから旧友の借金を
取り立てねえとならねえからな
Well, I only wish I knew what that meant.
さあ 何のことだか
巴衛！
Tomoe!
I'm more than happy to remind you, you ignorant fox!
頭の悪いきつねに
思い出させてやろう
526 years and 208 days ago at 18
minutes and 41 seconds past 2 AM,
526年と208日前
午前２時18分41秒
Tomoe, the spirit fox, attacked and wiped out seven dragons as well as three sharks,
妖狐(ようこ)巴衛
竜宮北門にて竜７頭他―
フカ３匹 エイ５匹
ウミウシ一個小隊を殺傷壊滅
five rays, and one sea slug platoon at the north gate of my palace.
He then destroyed the north gate
北門その他 建造物の破壊
and surrounding buildings of my palace.
被害は竜宮北の棟 ほぼ全壊
And finally, he stole my right eye from me,
Sukuna the Dragon King, and fled.
そして
この龍王宿儺(すくな)の右目を奪い逃走
I'm going to make sure you pay back this loan, plus interest, with your flesh and blood.
この貸し付けの代金
利子込みで
きっちり体で払ってもらうぜ
Giant White-Lipped Oyster!
王白蝶貝(おうしろちょうがい)！
ハハハッ
じわじわと貝の養分にされちまいな
You will slowly turn into sustenance for the Oyster now!
In two days or so, there'll be a
king-sized pearl all ready to go!
２日もすれば
特大真珠の出来上がりだ
Just what one would expect of Your Majesty, sea slug.
（ウミウシ１）
さすが龍王様ですウミウシ
The despicable wild fox was no threat to Your Majesty as you are now, sea slug.
（ウミウシ２）
にっくき野狐(やこ)めも―
今の龍王様の敵では
ありませんでしたウミウシ
Damn straight!
あたぼうよ　526年と208日間
毎日 筋トレしてたからな
For 526 years and 208 days straight, I've been doing strength training!
早速 竜宮に戻って
祝いのうたげだぜ
Now let's head back to the palace and have a celebratory banquet!
Sea slug!
（ウミウシたち）ウミウシ！
（奈々生）こら！
Hey!
What do you think you're doing to Tomoe?!
巴衛に何すんの
What's with that girl?
何だ あの娘は　なぜ起きている
Why is she awake?
巴衛を返せ
Give Tomoe back!
おっと
悪いが 見せ物はここまでだ
Ah!
Sorry, but the show's over.
So long, little girl!
じゃあな 小娘
I can't let them get away!
（奈々生）
行かせるものか 巴衛
Tomoe!
I cannot go into the ocean to protect you.
俺は海には入れない
That's what he said.
（奈々生）
言ってたのに 聞いてたのに
I didn't listen!
私が行かせた
I made him go!
It's scary to think that even with all his power...
あんなに強い巴衛が一瞬で
If I let go, I'll probably never see him again!
この手を離したら
きっと もう会えない
I can't breathe... Tomoe!
息が… 巴衛！
You are one persistent girl.
しつこい娘だな お前も
Knock it off already, all right?
（龍王）
いいかげんにしろよな
Where's Tomoe?
巴衛はどこ
I had the sea slugs transport him.
ウミウシどもに運ばせた
もういねえよ
He's long gone.
Yes, I did carry you to safety.
お前を ここまで運んでやったんだ
貸しにしとくぜ　いつか払え
You are welcome. Now you owe me.
Fine! Anything you want! Just give me Tomoe back!
ねえ お願い 巴衛を返して
（龍王）
あのきつねには
でっかい貸しがある
I'm afraid his debt is much larger than yours.
それを返してもらわねえと
筋が通らねえ
And I will not release him until it is paid in full.
（龍王）諦めな
（奈々生）どうすればいい？
Let it go.
What do I have to do?!
What do I have to do to get you to set him free?
どうすれば巴衛を返してくれる？
Since you asked...
そうだな
Return what is rightfully mine. Bring me back my right eye,
やつに取られた
俺の右目を返せば―
and I will consider sparing his miserable life.
命だけは
助けてやらねえこともねえかもな
My eye is a pill of eternal youth and immortality.
俺の目は不老長寿の丹
飲み込んだ者は
強力な力を得ると言われている
It's said that whoever swallows it will gain great powers.
All those years ago, I lost it to that insignificant spirit.
526年前 俺はそいつを
一介のあやかしに取られちまった
In other words, I, the Dragon King, had defeat carved into my face!
つまり この龍王が
顔に負けを刻まれたわけだ
All I have to do is return that eye,
and you'll spare Tomoe?
その目を返せば
巴衛を助けてくれるのね
All you have to do? As if it's that simple.
（龍王）
“その目を返せば”って
お前 簡単に言うな
It's been 526 years.
526年たってんだ
もう どうにかなっちまってるよ
I'm sure something's happened to it by now.
Like I said, just let it go.
つうわけで 諦めな
Wait!
（奈々生）待って
（龍王）ああ？
Huh?
Promise me.
約束して　目を取り戻せば
巴衛を助けてくれるって
If I can find the eye and return it, you'll let Tomoe live.
I don't know what you're planning to do, but...
どうする気か知らねえが
いいだろう　２日だけ
きつねを質ぐさに待ってやる
All right, then.
I'll hold the fox as collateral for two days only.
If that's the only way to save Tomoe, I have to find it.
（奈々生）
巴衛を助ける方法が１つだけある
Momiji lnn
（瑞希）
わあーっ
アイスって甘くておいしいね
僕 初めて食べたよ
Ice cream is so sweet and tasty!
It's my first time eating it.
Who the hell said you could be happy today?!
（ケイ）
何へらへらしてんだ こら
桃園と巴衛が
行方不明だっつってんのに―
Momozono and Tomoe are missing!
And you casually took a bath!
すっかり 風呂まで済ませやがって
Do you think we should call the police?
警察届けたほうがいいかな
I think it'll be fine.
大丈夫だと思うよ
Nanami will come back by tomorrow.
奈々生ちゃんは
あしたになったら帰ってくるよ
I'm going to sleep in the middle, okay?
僕 真ん中の布団で寝るね
寂しがり屋だから
Because I tend to get lonely.
We reserved this room for three girls.
この宿は女３人で予約してんだよ
You and Tomoe can find your own place to cuddle!
てめえと巴衛は ラブホで寝な
（ケイ）桃園
（あみ）奈々生ちゃん
Momozono!
Nanami!
Where have you been? Are you okay?
どこ行ってたの 大丈夫？
I'm sorry for making you worry.
（奈々生）
心配かけてごめんね　道に迷って
I got lost.
See? I told you she'd be fine.
ほら 大丈夫だって言ったじゃない
Mizuki!
（奈々生）瑞希
（瑞希）うん？
（奈々生）
時廻(ときまわ)りの香炉を貸してほしいの
Let me borrow the time-wending incense burner.
Momiji lnn
時廻りの香炉で
もう一度 過去に行って―
I have to go back in time and find the old Tomoe.
He has the Dragon King's eye,
and I'm gonna take it from him.
昔の巴衛から
龍王の目を奪い返すの
He said that if I returned his eye, he'd spare Tomoe's life.
龍王の目を返せば
巴衛の命は助けてくれるって
So please...
だから…
You know...
奈々生ちゃんてさ
巴衛君のこと好きなんだって？
I heard that you have feelings for Tomoe.
女の子に聞いたんだけど
One of the girls told me.
What?!
えっ
そ… そんなの今関係ないし か…
Th-Th-That has nothing to do
with what's going on right now!
A-A-A-And...
（瑞希）いいよね 巴衛君は
（奈々生）えっ
I think he's quite fortunate.
What?
こんなに愛してくれる
ご主人様がいてくれて憎たらしいな
He has a kind lady and mistress who loves him so much. I admit it hurts.
I hate Tomoe. I don't feel he deserves all that he has.
巴衛君のこと嫌いなんだよね 僕
If it were up to me, I would have him stay missing and consider it a small miracle.
このまま 僕の目の前から
消えてくれればいいって思ってるよ
What I'm feeling is probably
what they call jealousy or envy.
多分 この感情は
妬みとか嫉妬とかいうやつ
Have you ever felt that way about anyone?
奈々生ちゃんは誰かのこと
そういうふうに思ったことない？
教えてよ
Tell me.
この気持ちは
どうやったら治まるの？
What can I do to make this feeling go away?
I'm sorry.
（奈々生）
ごめん　私 瑞希に甘えてる
I'm asking a lot from you.
But even so, you're the only one I know who can help.
それでも 瑞希にしか頼めない
It's hard to say no when a god says that to you.
神様に それを言われると弱い
Messing with the past is quite taboo.
過去をいじくるのはタブーなんだ
But I doubt anyone will challenge you on it because you are a god.
でもまあ 神様のやることだから
とがめる人もいないでしょう
So you carry that thing with you?
持ってきてたんだ それ
I do.
Ever since my home got submerged, I've made it a rule to carry everything of value with me.
家が水没してから 大事なものは
持ち歩くことにしてるんだよね
前回は魂だけ飛ばしたけど―
Last time, I only sent your soul, but this time,
you'll be going over there as your corporeal self.
今回は実体のまま あちらに行く
I'll accompany you, but I'll only be your guide.
僕もお供するけど
ただのガイドだからね
You'll have to do the rest.
あとのことは自分でやりな
Tomoe...
（奈々生）
巴衛
Tomoe.
In the light...
光の中―
all I can see is you.
あなたしか見えない
I love you so deeply...
こんなに
どうしようもないくらい―
and so hopelessly, and yet...
あなたが好きなのに
I will not ever allow myself to love a human woman.
（巴衛）
人間の女なんか 好きにならないよ
寒い！
It's so cold!
I-If it's snowing, it looks like I made it into the past without any problems, but...
ゆ… 雪が降ってるってことは
無事に過去に来られたっぽいけど
M-Mizuki?
み… 瑞希　瑞希は？
Where's Mizuki?
You must be cold in such light clothing.
（磯姫(いそひめ)）
そんな薄着で寒かろうが
You must want this cloak.
この かずきが欲しかろう？
What?
（磯姫）
お前の中にある その龍王の目
The Dragon King's eye inside of you...
私にくれたら あげてもいいよ
Give it to me, and in return, I'll give you this cloak.
What?
（瑞希）
奈々生ちゃーん！
Nanami!
Nanami?
奈々生ちゃん？
Don't go wandering off. It's dangerous.
はぐれないでよ 危ないな
Mizuki, there was a woman here just now.
（奈々生）
瑞希　今 女の人がいたんだけど
That was a spirit named Isohime.
（瑞希）
あれは磯姫って妖怪
She can often be found waiting by the
seashore for lost and vulnerable humans.
海辺でよく かもになる
人間を待ち伏せしてるんだ
Now shouldn't you be out looking for Tomoe?
いいの？　巴衛君 捜さなくて
That's right! I have to find Tomoe!
そうだ　巴衛 見つけなきゃ
Tomoe!
（イソギンチャク）
巴衛！
How dare you raid our palace?!
よくも我らの宮殿を荒らしたな
龍王様の右目を返せー！
Return the Dragon King's right eye!
（巴衛）
フンッ
お前たちに構ってる暇はない
I have no time to bother with you.
ah ah ah ah
The same face.
（奈々生）
同じ顔
The same voice.
ah ah ah ah
巴衛
Tomoe...
He's...
彼が…
ah ah ah ah
the one I love
まだ闇の中にいる
ah ah ah ah
who's still in darkness.
私の好きな人
ah ah ah ah
Nanami.
奈々生さん
ah ah ah ah
Promise. Promise me you'll look after Tomoe.
どうか どうか巴衛を頼みますよ
ah ah ah ah
kamisama onegai da
Please, God
boku no
I...
ano hito ni aitai no sa
I want to meet her
ah ah ah
ah ah ah ah
kamisama tsurain da
God, I'm in pain
kyou mo mata nou ni
Because, she...
konakatta
didn't come today either.
onegai ga aru no kamisama
I have a request, God
boku wo tasukete
Please, save me
ah ah ah ah
kamisama mou osoi
God, it's too late for me
ano ko wa...
Because she's...
Preview
In search of the Dragon King's right eye,
Nanami and Mizuki have traveled to the past.
（講釈師）
龍王の右目を探しに―
Touku sora ni
gone off into the distant sky
過去の世界にやって来た
奈々生と瑞希
そこには巴衛と
横には美しい女性が
There, they find Tomoe and a beautiful woman by his side.
Kieta no sa
and disappeared
Argh! Who the hell is that woman?!
きーっ！　何よあの女
立ち直れるか 奈々生
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Will Nanami recover?!
次回「神様、竜宮城にいく」
Next time, "The God Goes To The Dragon King's Palace."
The God Goes To The Dragon King's Palace
Sayonara baby
Farewell, baby
Beauty too great to do justice to in a painting.
絵にもかけない美しさ♪
Goodbye